<topics>
    <topic>
        <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-asylums</id>
        <!--This XML file contains the results of the Chronicling America Asylums project.
        It includes 10 pre-selected articles and 5 query-based results, with relevance judgments and excerpts.
        -->
        <results>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93067790/1872-02-14/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Asylum+Lunatic</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    "I make these extracts to show the
                    penurious plan upon which our insane an?
                    provided for, and how insignificant the
                    sum now asked from the State, for the
                    support of our Asylum for the current
                    year, when compared with the cost of
                    other similar institutions, as well as to
                    show the littleness )f soul of those immaculato
                    law-makers, ami patterns of
                    official economy, who are opposed to giv¬
                    ing to the insane that aid which humani¬
                    ty demands, and which the honor id' the
                    State cannot afford to withhold.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87076917/1888-06-22/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=asylum+lunatic+women</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Lizzie Shay, who attempted suicide at
                    the station bouse, was brought before Pro
                    bata Judge Miller last eveniugandadjudged
                    Insane. She will be sent to the Day tin
                    asylum, iter lnunity is not violent, but
                    she manifests a coustant disposition to run
                    away.
                    In almost every lunatic asylum the
                    women greatly ontnuinber the men. not
                    only because they are so long lived, but
                    also because they are so seldom cured
                    It commonly surprises visitors to a
                    lunatic asylum to find that insane people
                    are not for a moment deceive.! by the do
                    lusious of their fellow patients Each
                    will think himself perfectly sane and
                    thy, while kuowinc that all the others
                    oro hopelessly mad
                    It is a novel experience to attend a religious
                    service at an insane asylum Imagine
                    a congregation of lunatics and lm
                    beetles, men uu one Udu, women- on the
                    other, in all stages of physical decay and
                    all degrees of madness Helpless, old.
                    gray haired fellows, with staring sunken
                    eyes and hollow ckeeks, mumbling and
                    groaning to themselves. In utter nncon
                    sclousness of their surroundings Gaunt
                    looking, wild eyed women, with nothing
                    human about them but their vanity
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1888-07-30/ed-2/?sp=1&amp;q=asylum+ASYLUM+Asylum+death+DEATH</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Coroner Levy was notified this morning of
                    a mysterious death in the City Asylum for
                    the Insane on Ward's iBland, which it Is
                    claimed is tho result of foul play by tho
                    keepers.
                    Lawyer O'Dwyer said there many bruises
                    on tho man's body which boro out the wifo's
                    suspicious, and urged that n rigid investiga-tio- n
                    be mode
                    Coroner Levy is informed that some timo
                    ago Willis was attacked with tho persecution
                    mania and wastakou to tho Middletown Insane
                    Asylum, hut was subsequently reinovod
                    to the Amityvillc asylum. There a oomplaint
                    was mado against him and ho was removed'to
                    his home.
                    While walking in the street three months
                    ago he began to act strangely, and n citizen
                    bod him arrested.
                    Ho was sent to Bellevuo Hospital, where he
                    was pronounced insane, and was removed to
                    tho Ward's Island Asylum.
                    Mrs. Willis Tisitod nor husband at tho institution
                    last Tuesday, when he was apparently
                    in good health. Ho comclainod to
                    Lor of the brutal treatmont he received at
                    tho hands of the attendants and exhibited to
                    her several bruises. She returned to her
                    home very much broken down.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1900-10-06/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Feeble+Feeble-minded+minded</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Montee Ledderhos, though but four,
                    years of age, has been adjudged a maniac by
                    the Insanity Commission.
                    Members
                    of the Insanity Commission zvho examined
                    him, however, arc unable at this time, owing
                    partly to the absence of a detailed clinical history
                    of the case, to advance a positive opinion
                    as to the cause of his malady. Since the
                    child's injury he has been constantly under
                    the care of physicians. 'Everything known to
                    medical science zvhich zvas zvithin the pozver
                    of his parents' limited means to procure zvas
                    tried in the hope of at least relieving, even
                    though a complete cure zvas impossible, the
                    sufferings of their baby. Allefforts to aid
                    him haz'c been futile,herzvever, and the fight to
                    secure his commitment to an asylum has just
                    been won. Inall probability the remainder of
                    his years on earth zvill be passed behind the
                    bars of a madhouse.
                    Homicidal and suicidal mania have
                    caused Montee Ledderhos' relatives to seek his
                    imprisonment. Since his birth he has not spoken, but endeavors
                    to express himself by means of unintelligible
                    noises. His murderous inclinations
                    prcz'entcd his admission into the Asylum for
                    the Feeble-minded, and in the absence of a better
                    remedy or safer home he zvill be committed
                    to the asylum.
                    InNapa Asylum, however, his jangled mind may take full sway, but by
                    to-night that institution may harbor a scene unparalleled throughout these
                    fr.lsed States— tb« s=eene of a baby boy, his tiny arms he'.d fast in leathern
                    p'raps, pacing the floor of an asylum cell with no one but himself on whom
                    to vent his lust for murder
                    Dr. Rothers was called upon to make an examination
                    of th« child. He immediately pronounced the lad insane, and
                    with Dr. Lustig: signed the certificate setting forth the nature' of the
                    chTTd's malady. This preliminary disposed of, the commitment was drawn
                    up. The little patient was led back to Mrs. Barbee's home to await the
                    coming of the Sheriff, who will take him to the asylum. The commitment
                    willbe presented to Judge Lawlor this morning. His signature will be
                    aflixed and Jlttlc Montee Ledderhos will leave his birthplace to go to/ the
                    home where in all probability the remaining years of his life will be
                    passed.
                    "The asylum for the insane is plainly the place for him. HI3 mania is
                    to destroy, to kill and to maim .himself. There is no doubj that he will
                    be a source of endless worry to the management of the Napa Asylum, and
                    Ifear that the trouble he willcause may result- in a demand being made
                    that he be discharged from that Institution and committed to the Home for
                    the Feeble-minded. Though there is no doubt that the ;Home for the
                    Feeble-minded is better fitted for the care of such 1 youngsters —or rather
                    simple-minded youngsters— in my opinion the only safe place to keep him
                    is in the asylum. His mania at any moment might cause him to seek"
                    gratification .among tho helpless Inmates of the Home, for the Feebleminded,
                    and even though he may be the source of endless worry to the asylum officials,
                    for humanity's sake he should be allowed to remain there until the end."
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99066033/1901-12-14/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=asylum</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    No matter how fretful or trying an
                    inmate may be the attendant in charge
                    must be cheerful, firm and kind. Foibles
                    and pet fancies of the sufferers
                    must be scrupulously regarded. Anger
                    or loss of temper by the employes
                    makes the patients fretful and ctoss
                    as well as dissatisfied. For this reason
                    Dr. Greene has insisted on kind
                    treatment under all circumstances.
                    Female attendants are now required
                    to dress In the regulation nurse uniform.
                    This consists of a dress of blue
                    and white material. A white apron
                    and white collar are worn as well as
                    a white lace cap If preferable.
                    At present the attendants, both male
                    and female, are required to study then
                    Patients closely and are given a course
                    f Instruction by Superintendent
                    Greene, in addition to the advice they
                    receive from their superiors. Inexperienced
                    help, afterwards properl
                    drilled, is preferred and faithfulness
                    and ability will lead to their retention.
                    It has been found that raw material
                    Is more susceptible to instruction and
                    more eager to learn the duties required.
                    pillow slips
                    washed, the closets disinfected according
                    to the most approved hygienic
                    rules. The bath tubs in the new building
                    are porcelain. All the floors and
                    corridors receive careful attention.
                    In the kitchen the cleanliness Is most
                    striking. All the tables upon which
                    carving or serving is done, are zinc
                    covered. These are washed off with
                    scalding hot water after each meal.
                    Milk cans are subjected to a sterializ-in- g
                    process after the contents have
                    been removed. The large steel range
                    has been moved out from the wall and
                    an opening made so that the accumulation
                    of dirt behind the stove may be
                    prevented. The kitchen has been provided
                    with the latest Improvements in
                    the way of steam cooking. From the
                    kitchen the food Is transported to the
                    serving room of the dining halls
                    through tunnels on small cars.
                    The atmosphere of the parlor
                    and dormitory is almost as pure as
                    the air out of doors. In the matter of
                    plumbing the state has secured excellent
                    service.
                    In the bastment of the new wing Is
                    the dining room where the women eat.
                    At the tap of the bell they fall In line
                    and march to the tables. They remain
                    standing until the second ringing of the
                    bell. Then supper begins.
                    Wholesome food, well cooked, unlimited
                    in quantity, is furnished to all.
                    .Milk toast and beef tea Is always at
                    hand to tempt the appetites of the delicate.
                    The attendants watch the patients
                    closely and urge them to eat.
                    When the meal Is finished the patients
                    arise. Hefore they leave the room
                    the knives and forks are counted to
                    make sure that none are carried away.
                    When this is done the patients are
                    inarched back to the parlors.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1906-05-05/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=ABUSE+ASYLUM</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Mr Burroughs claimed that he saw
                    R an employe of the aamdry strike patients with his flat
                    beat them with towels and pillow cases oar the head and then put them
                    through the wringing out process
                    Herbert Spencer when he went on the
                    stand testified under oath that he saw
                    NktientE strapped te beds in Howard
                    Sail the steeping apartments of the
                    nomattal sw them placed fct strait-
                    Jackets sad teadcuffed Ha said that
                    the patterns xRes toR when strappedto
                    bed radical pain
                    The patients were strapped head and toot sad in such a position that they could not move He asserted that
                    he saw De Sales Lyons a colored
                    of the laundry wring out patients
                    and otherwise punish them In adtaaraceful
                    way
                    The pushing car method of punish
                    lair employes was administered by Sill
                    lard Sidney an employe of the laundry
                    On croes caranetfon lie said that he
                    only saw one patient strapped in bed
                    and only one placed In a straitjacket
                    though he noticed that there were
                    straitjaekets in the laundry
                    they having been sent there to be
                    The most pointed statements were
                    made bjr T L MeMurray who said
                    that he iron employed in the laundry
                    for four and a half years The
                    under oath stated that he saw
                    air SatterfieM tower and otherwise
                    punish Alphonso Rollins a number o
                    times On one occasion he saw Satter
                    field knock Rollns down and choke him
                    He said he saw several other patients
                    maltreated by Ute wrtngnso and
                    pushingear system He said that he
                    saw Foreman Maenche drunk on
                    occasions and in condition unfit
                    for the performance of his duties
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025661/1840-11-18/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=asylum+lunatic</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    We have had
                    1 puients recover," who, had made.
                    ; roverrierit the "first yea f.,' One 'pa-- .
                    '
                    w;i s b ro u ghl ' to t h e asy 1 Um i n Jn n e,
                    o. nr (iiiu ut'CD insane iwo years,
                    duririg the last' several months was
                    ialent ps to b: caged and chained. ooii
                    a3 he was placed in th asylum.
                    r,i3 pat under, a reqruUr coarse of
                    ! merit, bat no radical clnnge xccured
                    the first two years of his' residence
                    lis place.'" w J unci 1810, he was" a ly
                    in ihach the state'of mind as' he
                    ,it the time of his admission, although
                    !.ab"as had ; improved Soon af;er h'
                    n to improve, and in September he
                    disch.irg.'d entirely well. Had he
                    i removed al tfle end of six-month- as
                    sualfy the'ease, 'and been returned, to
                    former' cage, he would jindoultedly
                    e rem lined insane through life. This,
                    other f.icls, prove that old "cases are
                    necessarily incurableand that-eom- e
                    er under the most discouraging cir- -
                    'ance?; therefore a reasonable trial
                    1 i i . . .
                    1 ma.se itn them.,
                    --Duiing ihis lime two hundred and
                    ihirty-nin- e patien'shave received the benefits
                    of the asylum. Among1 these we
                    have hnd patients " manifesting every condition
                    of insanity, from the lowest state of
                    imbecility, by which he is incapable of attending
                    even to the wants of life, to the
                    violent and furious madman, ,: who, reckless
                    of consequences,- - exposes himself lo
                    all the dangers which are connected with
                    such a state. And worst of all, we have
                    had those suicidal ca?es, seeking every opportunity
                    of self-destructio- n,
                    , which an excited
                    and diseased imagination could in
                    vent.1 Nolwfthstandnig al! the dangers and
                    accidents to which, we have; been exposed,
                    nO'patlent has died from suicide, or accidental
                    injury. '. "'
                    T
                    , :.'.'. There are provided at the asylum, the '
                    usual means for amusements ; and exer-fcis- .'.
                    Bul the best moral means we have
                    found for the benefit of the patients,' is use-f- u
                    1 - employment ' 'in 1 the ope.n . air.; , Employment
                    on the farm' has contributed very
                    much to the promotion of the health
                    and recovery t our male patients. . It.re-- .
                    Iievesthe irksomeness. of confinement,
                    makes them pleasant' and cheerful, j'm- -
                    proves their! health, and promotes their recovery.!
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1908-08-02/ed-1/?sp=40&amp;q=asylum+lunatic</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn96088376/1908-01-31/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=asylum+ASYLUM+Asylum+Death+death+DEATHS</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Within my recollection several attendants
                    have contracted tuberculosis
                    and died. Whetheror not these
                    deaths were due to Improper conditions
                    at the asylum- - It Is Impossible
                    to say as the same persons might
                    havs contracted it had they resided
                    elsewhere.
                    The asylum Is always crowded and
                    considering present conditions, th
                    work along thla line during th past
                    year deserves commendation. Much
                    remains to be done, however, before
                    th medical staff 1 properly equipped
                    to prevent th ravages of thla
                    terrible malady.
                    I found no laboratory or pathologic
                    apparatus ot any kind but th superintendent.
                    Dr. Stelner. told me that
                    practical working outfit had been ordered
                    and would be Installed and put
                    Into us at the earliest possible date.
                    ' The Ideal way to handle th tuberculosis
                    cases at th asylum would b
                    In cottages apart from th main
                    building; thla would involve a considerable
                    expenditure of money both for
                    first cost and maintenance and
                    would hardly meet the approval of
                    the average legislator. A much leas
                    expensive plan and - one efficient,
                    would be to construct open air pavilions
                    adjoining the infirmary.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn97065122/1920-07-24/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Asylum+death</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/moldovan-collection-at-the-library-of-congress/about-moldova</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/french-collections/books-france</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-asylums/introduction</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/latinx-civil-rights/cuban-adjustment-act</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026965/1887-10-20/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1789&amp;index=8&amp;date2=1924&amp;searchType=advanced&amp;language=&amp;sequence=1&amp;words=Blackwell+bly+Island+Nellie&amp;proxdistance=5&amp;rows=20&amp;ortext=&amp;proxtext=&amp;phrasetext=Blackwells+Island&amp;andtext=Nellie+Bly&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
        </results>
    </topic>
    <topic>
        <!--This XML file contains the results of the Chronicling American april fools origin.
        It includes 10 pre-selected articles and 5 query-based results, with relevance judgments and excerpts.
        -->
        <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-april-fools</id>
        <results>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85034039/1871-04-21/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+fools+pranks&amp;r=0.339,0.401,0.698,0.408,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026994/1873-04-01/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=april+pranks+fools</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    The origin or "April Fool" ia as remote
                    aod as impossible to determine as the birth¬
                    day of the first fool who marred Nature's
                    original design of intellectual Man. We
                    trace it everywhere; but the Beeret hour of
                    its birth bafiles research. We are forced to
                    admit its existence, without being able to
                    assign a cause. The Romans undoubtedly
                    enjoyed its questionable fun. They cer¬
                    tainly carried its memory in all their con¬
                    quests. Its observance was long cherished
                    among numeróos nations. Abandoned to
                    the yalgar in our self-elected age of extreme
                    refinement,
                    using itself as a trowel to cement tbe crum ti¬
                    ling Kellogg platform ; striking the first
                    blow lo insure its own annihilation. April
                    Fool I Louisiana issalog addresses and
                    sending representatives to the Union at
                    large, convinced that her distress must be
                    of National in ten ;t. April Fool 1
                    Amadeos accepting the Spanish Grown'
                    which bas so loog been unsettled that ils
                    balance cac not be determined; giving a
                    gratuitous kick to accelerate ita certain fall.
                    April Fooll Spanish Cortes insisting OD
                    the recognition "de facto'? of a republic
                    which does not exist "de jure;" selling op
                    a ten-pio Republic for ihe mero sport of
                    bowling it down. April Fool !
                    England's tories and whigs doing their
                    best to destroy the ablest minister of the
                    Crown on the question of the Irish Univer¬
                    sity; paying tilhes of "mint, annis and
                    "cummin" while neglecting the weightier
                    matters of tbe law. April Fool !
                    France with Thiers more iban king, shoot¬
                    ing itself hoarse wilh "Vive la République 1
                    "A bas l'Empire I A bas la monarchie I"
                    April Fool !
                    Ukraine peasants revolting against an
                    îutocrat who owns half the Continent of
                    Surope; ramming themselves lalo monars"
                    br the mere chance of being discharged at
                    heir masters' heads. April Fool !
                    Each nation convinced that "the Parlia-
                    "mentof Man, and Federation of the world"
                    s to be convoked ander its own vine and tig
                    :ree. April Fool 1
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014635/1894-04-01/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=april+fools+pranks&amp;r=-0.297,0.166,1.638,0.956,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-04-02/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=april+fool+pranks&amp;r=-0.79,-0.195,2.58,1.506,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1900-04-01/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=april+fool+pranks&amp;r=-0.765,-0.101,2.529,1.477,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Wlatlon to each other.
                    A learned antiquary, writing in 1599,
                    claims that our AprilFools' day Is but a
                    continuation of the Qulrinalla, or feast of
                    fools, bf the ancient Romans. In-"The
                    British Apollo." a most ingenious work
                    published !n 17C8.
                    ""Whence proceeds the custom of making
                    April fools? Answer: From a memorable
                    transaction happening between
                    " the
                    Romans and the Sabine.3, mentioned by
                    Dionysius. Which was thus: The Romans,
                    about the Infancy of their city, wanting
                    wives, and finding they could not obtain
                    the neighboring women by their peaceable
                    addresses, resolved to make use of stratagem,
                    and accordingly Romulus instituted
                    certain games to be performed in the beginning
                    of April(according to the Roman
                    calendar) in honor of Neptune. Upon notice
                    thereof the bordqring Inhabitants,
                    with their whole families, flocked to Rome
                    to see this mighty celebration, whereupon
                    the Romans seized a number of the Sablna
                    virgins and ravished them, which imposition,
                    we suppose, may be the foundation
                    of this foolish custom." This most absurd
                    and wholly unjustifiable account of the
                    origin of making April fools is thus ridiculed
                    by a poet of the time:
                    Some old folk-writers claim that our
                    AprilFool customs are attributable to the
                    fact that the year formerly began, as to
                    come purposes and in some respects, on
                    the 25th of March, which was supposed
                    ?o be the day of Our Lord's incarnation.
                    At that time' it was customary for all
                    festivals to continue for an octave, or period of eight days. April1 Is the
                    octave of March 25, and the last day
                    of a festival octavo was always marked
                    by the greatest abandon and festivity.
                    At the New Year season especially all
                    sorts of wild, mirthful pranks were Indulged
                    In, and of these Itis believed that
                    our April fool usages - were a part.
                    Origins of a religious nature have been
                    boldly claimed for April Fools' day by
                    many writers. An old English antiquary,
                    writingIn1753. states that the custom of
                    imposing upon and ridiculing people on
                    the Ist of Aprilmay have an allusion to
                    the mockery of the Savior of the world
                    by the Jews. Something like that which
                    we call making April fools Is practiced
                    also abroad in Catholic countries on Innocents'
                    day, on which occasion people
                    run through all the rooms, making a pretended
                    search in and under the beds. In
                    memory, Ibelieve, of the search made by
                    Herod for the discovery and the destruction
                    of the child Jesus and of his having
                    been imposed upon and deceived by the
                    wise men, who, contrary to his orders
                    and expectation, "returned to their own
                    country another way.
                    When the early Britons were Induced to
                    forsake' their Druidical priests and Idols
                    and to embrace Christianity, It was their
                    custom" for many years after to annually
                    hold in their churches at the commencement
                    of April a great festival, resembling
                    the Roman Saturnalia, at which
                    they indulged in a thousand ridiculous
                    and indecent ceremonies, gambols and
                    dancing grotesquely to ludicrous anthems.
                    These singular observances referred to the
                    exploded pretensions of the Druids, whom
                    this
                    '
                    festival was designed to hold up to
                    scorn and derision. That there Is no more
                    effective weapon than ridicule was again
                    proved In this case, for this feast of fools
                    the heathen religion and its priests than
                    all the collateral aids of fire and sword,
                    though they were also freely employed.
                    The continuance of customs? especially
                    droll ones, which suit the gross taste of
                    the masses? after the original cause of
                    them has been removed. Is a very common
                    occurence. and by many antiquaries It is
                    firmly believed that "fooling" people on
                    the Ist of Aprilis simply a perpetuation
                    of the annual public ridiculing of the old
                    Druid's and their superstitions.
                    Still another oripin. of a semi-religious
                    character, 13 thus claimed for AprilFools'
                    day In a quaint old book of folk-lore called "Father Time's Flyghtes." published
                    in London In 1659. "numerous Jewish Origin of the Custom of Making
                    Fools on the First of April. This is said
                    to have begun from "ye mistake of Noah sending ye dove out before ye water had
                    abated, on ye first day of ye month which
                    among ye Hebrews answers to our first
                    of April,and to perpetrate ye memory of
                    this deliverance it was thought proper
                    whoever forgot so remarkable a circumstance
                    to punish them by sending them upon some fool's errand similar to- the
                    Ineffectual message upon which ye bird was sent by ye patriarch."
                    The French associate with the first of Aprilprecisely the same Ideas as do Enr llsh speaking nations, but the person Im- posed upon, whom we call an April FcJ*. they style an AprilFl3h or Polsson d' -vril.
                    In the "Etymology of French proverbs,"
                    a most curious and delightful
                    work published In 1356. Billlngton Ithe
                    author, gives the following expiation
                    of the origin of AprilFool customs / "The
                    word poisson is corrupted throtffn the
                    Ignorance of the people from pasr'on. and length of time has almost totall- defaced
                    the original intention, which w^ as follows:
                    That as the Passion of c-n* Saviour
                    took place about this time o'the year,
                    and as the Jews sent Chris*; backward
                    and forward to mock and't->rment him.
                    1. c., from Annns to Caiaph?*». from Caiaphas
                    to Pilate, from Pilate -°- Herod and
                    from Herod back to Pilate, this ridiculous
                    or rather Impious custorrAook Its rise
                    from thence, by which we send about
                    from one place to anoO«r such persona
                    aa we think proper subjects of our ridicule."
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085187/1909-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+fools+pranks&amp;r=-0.802,0.103,2.604,1.52,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-04-02/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+fools+pranks</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066313/1915-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+foolls+prank&amp;r=-1.244,-0.018,3.489,1.628,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    According io me map wmcu
                    U p Wrench has prepared and kept
                    In the corridor of the third floor of
                    Academic Hall, European armies have
                    made radical changes in their maneuvers.
                    The French apparently have
                    given up the war and have fled to the
                    western coast of France. The English
                    have disappeared entirely. All
                    the German forces of the western
                    theater are quartered in Paris. In the
                    east, the Austrian and German forces
                    are massed in the lowlands of Prussia,
                    surrounded by Russian and Ser
                    vian troops. A few Servians are left
                    as garrisons along the frontier. One
                    lone Austrian army corps has escaped
                    and is now stationed in the middle of
                    the North Sea.
                    The havoc Is attributed to some
                    April Fool prank.
                    Another Instance of April Fool
                    thoughtfulness was shown this morning
                    when a member of the Agricultural
                    faculty phoned to the county
                    jail asking "who had left a call for
                    him."
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88084272/1916-04-01/ed-1/?sp=14&amp;q=april+fools+parks&amp;r=-0.811,-0.046,2.621,1.224,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058393/1922-04-01/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=april+fools+pranks</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <!--The queries matched with the 10 articles I documented,
            could be because of the niche topic-->
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066313/1915-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+foolls+prank&amp;r=-1.244,-0.018,3.489,1.628,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    According io me map wmcu
                    U p Wrench has prepared and kept
                    In the corridor of the third floor of
                    Academic Hall, European armies have
                    made radical changes in their maneuvers.
                    The French apparently have
                    given up the war and have fled to the
                    western coast of France. The English
                    have disappeared entirely. All
                    the German forces of the western
                    theater are quartered in Paris. In the
                    east, the Austrian and German forces
                    are massed in the lowlands of Prussia,
                    surrounded by Russian and Ser
                    vian troops. A few Servians are left
                    as garrisons along the frontier. One
                    lone Austrian army corps has escaped
                    and is now stationed in the middle of
                    the North Sea.
                    The havoc Is attributed to some
                    April Fool prank.
                    Another Instance of April Fool
                    thoughtfulness was shown this morning
                    when a member of the Agricultural
                    faculty phoned to the county
                    jail asking "who had left a call for
                    him."
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014635/1894-04-01/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=april+fools+pranks&amp;r=-0.297,0.166,1.638,0.956,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-04-02/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=april+fool+pranks&amp;r=-0.79,-0.195,2.58,1.506,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
        </results>
    </topic>
</topics>
