<topics>
    <topic>
        <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-asylums</id>
        <!--This XML file contains the results of the Chronicling America Asylums project.
        It includes 10 pre-selected articles and 5 query-based results, with relevance judgments and excerpts.
        -->
        <results>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93067790/1872-02-14/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Asylum+Lunatic</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    "I make these extracts to show the
                    penurious plan upon which our insane an?
                    provided for, and how insignificant the
                    sum now asked from the State, for the
                    support of our Asylum for the current
                    year, when compared with the cost of
                    other similar institutions, as well as to
                    show the littleness )f soul of those immaculato
                    law-makers, ami patterns of
                    official economy, who are opposed to giv¬
                    ing to the insane that aid which humani¬
                    ty demands, and which the honor id' the
                    State cannot afford to withhold.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87076917/1888-06-22/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=asylum+lunatic+women</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Lizzie Shay, who attempted suicide at
                    the station bouse, was brought before Pro
                    bata Judge Miller last eveniugandadjudged
                    Insane. She will be sent to the Day tin
                    asylum, iter lnunity is not violent, but
                    she manifests a coustant disposition to run
                    away.
                    In almost every lunatic asylum the
                    women greatly ontnuinber the men. not
                    only because they are so long lived, but
                    also because they are so seldom cured
                    It commonly surprises visitors to a
                    lunatic asylum to find that insane people
                    are not for a moment deceive.! by the do
                    lusious of their fellow patients Each
                    will think himself perfectly sane and
                    thy, while kuowinc that all the others
                    oro hopelessly mad
                    It is a novel experience to attend a religious
                    service at an insane asylum Imagine
                    a congregation of lunatics and lm
                    beetles, men uu one Udu, women- on the
                    other, in all stages of physical decay and
                    all degrees of madness Helpless, old.
                    gray haired fellows, with staring sunken
                    eyes and hollow ckeeks, mumbling and
                    groaning to themselves. In utter nncon
                    sclousness of their surroundings Gaunt
                    looking, wild eyed women, with nothing
                    human about them but their vanity
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1888-07-30/ed-2/?sp=1&amp;q=asylum+ASYLUM+Asylum+death+DEATH</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Coroner Levy was notified this morning of
                    a mysterious death in the City Asylum for
                    the Insane on Ward's iBland, which it Is
                    claimed is tho result of foul play by tho
                    keepers.
                    Lawyer O'Dwyer said there many bruises
                    on tho man's body which boro out the wifo's
                    suspicious, and urged that n rigid investiga-tio- n
                    be mode
                    Coroner Levy is informed that some timo
                    ago Willis was attacked with tho persecution
                    mania and wastakou to tho Middletown Insane
                    Asylum, hut was subsequently reinovod
                    to the Amityvillc asylum. There a oomplaint
                    was mado against him and ho was removed'to
                    his home.
                    While walking in the street three months
                    ago he began to act strangely, and n citizen
                    bod him arrested.
                    Ho was sent to Bellevuo Hospital, where he
                    was pronounced insane, and was removed to
                    tho Ward's Island Asylum.
                    Mrs. Willis Tisitod nor husband at tho institution
                    last Tuesday, when he was apparently
                    in good health. Ho comclainod to
                    Lor of the brutal treatmont he received at
                    tho hands of the attendants and exhibited to
                    her several bruises. She returned to her
                    home very much broken down.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1900-10-06/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Feeble+Feeble-minded+minded</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Montee Ledderhos, though but four,
                    years of age, has been adjudged a maniac by
                    the Insanity Commission.
                    Members
                    of the Insanity Commission zvho examined
                    him, however, arc unable at this time, owing
                    partly to the absence of a detailed clinical history
                    of the case, to advance a positive opinion
                    as to the cause of his malady. Since the
                    child's injury he has been constantly under
                    the care of physicians. 'Everything known to
                    medical science zvhich zvas zvithin the pozver
                    of his parents' limited means to procure zvas
                    tried in the hope of at least relieving, even
                    though a complete cure zvas impossible, the
                    sufferings of their baby. Allefforts to aid
                    him haz'c been futile,herzvever, and the fight to
                    secure his commitment to an asylum has just
                    been won. Inall probability the remainder of
                    his years on earth zvill be passed behind the
                    bars of a madhouse.
                    Homicidal and suicidal mania have
                    caused Montee Ledderhos' relatives to seek his
                    imprisonment. Since his birth he has not spoken, but endeavors
                    to express himself by means of unintelligible
                    noises. His murderous inclinations
                    prcz'entcd his admission into the Asylum for
                    the Feeble-minded, and in the absence of a better
                    remedy or safer home he zvill be committed
                    to the asylum.
                    InNapa Asylum, however, his jangled mind may take full sway, but by
                    to-night that institution may harbor a scene unparalleled throughout these
                    fr.lsed States— tb« s=eene of a baby boy, his tiny arms he'.d fast in leathern
                    p'raps, pacing the floor of an asylum cell with no one but himself on whom
                    to vent his lust for murder
                    Dr. Rothers was called upon to make an examination
                    of th« child. He immediately pronounced the lad insane, and
                    with Dr. Lustig: signed the certificate setting forth the nature' of the
                    chTTd's malady. This preliminary disposed of, the commitment was drawn
                    up. The little patient was led back to Mrs. Barbee's home to await the
                    coming of the Sheriff, who will take him to the asylum. The commitment
                    willbe presented to Judge Lawlor this morning. His signature will be
                    aflixed and Jlttlc Montee Ledderhos will leave his birthplace to go to/ the
                    home where in all probability the remaining years of his life will be
                    passed.
                    "The asylum for the insane is plainly the place for him. HI3 mania is
                    to destroy, to kill and to maim .himself. There is no doubj that he will
                    be a source of endless worry to the management of the Napa Asylum, and
                    Ifear that the trouble he willcause may result- in a demand being made
                    that he be discharged from that Institution and committed to the Home for
                    the Feeble-minded. Though there is no doubt that the ;Home for the
                    Feeble-minded is better fitted for the care of such 1 youngsters —or rather
                    simple-minded youngsters— in my opinion the only safe place to keep him
                    is in the asylum. His mania at any moment might cause him to seek"
                    gratification .among tho helpless Inmates of the Home, for the Feebleminded,
                    and even though he may be the source of endless worry to the asylum officials,
                    for humanity's sake he should be allowed to remain there until the end."
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99066033/1901-12-14/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=asylum</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    No matter how fretful or trying an
                    inmate may be the attendant in charge
                    must be cheerful, firm and kind. Foibles
                    and pet fancies of the sufferers
                    must be scrupulously regarded. Anger
                    or loss of temper by the employes
                    makes the patients fretful and ctoss
                    as well as dissatisfied. For this reason
                    Dr. Greene has insisted on kind
                    treatment under all circumstances.
                    Female attendants are now required
                    to dress In the regulation nurse uniform.
                    This consists of a dress of blue
                    and white material. A white apron
                    and white collar are worn as well as
                    a white lace cap If preferable.
                    At present the attendants, both male
                    and female, are required to study then
                    Patients closely and are given a course
                    f Instruction by Superintendent
                    Greene, in addition to the advice they
                    receive from their superiors. Inexperienced
                    help, afterwards properl
                    drilled, is preferred and faithfulness
                    and ability will lead to their retention.
                    It has been found that raw material
                    Is more susceptible to instruction and
                    more eager to learn the duties required.
                    pillow slips
                    washed, the closets disinfected according
                    to the most approved hygienic
                    rules. The bath tubs in the new building
                    are porcelain. All the floors and
                    corridors receive careful attention.
                    In the kitchen the cleanliness Is most
                    striking. All the tables upon which
                    carving or serving is done, are zinc
                    covered. These are washed off with
                    scalding hot water after each meal.
                    Milk cans are subjected to a sterializ-in- g
                    process after the contents have
                    been removed. The large steel range
                    has been moved out from the wall and
                    an opening made so that the accumulation
                    of dirt behind the stove may be
                    prevented. The kitchen has been provided
                    with the latest Improvements in
                    the way of steam cooking. From the
                    kitchen the food Is transported to the
                    serving room of the dining halls
                    through tunnels on small cars.
                    The atmosphere of the parlor
                    and dormitory is almost as pure as
                    the air out of doors. In the matter of
                    plumbing the state has secured excellent
                    service.
                    In the bastment of the new wing Is
                    the dining room where the women eat.
                    At the tap of the bell they fall In line
                    and march to the tables. They remain
                    standing until the second ringing of the
                    bell. Then supper begins.
                    Wholesome food, well cooked, unlimited
                    in quantity, is furnished to all.
                    .Milk toast and beef tea Is always at
                    hand to tempt the appetites of the delicate.
                    The attendants watch the patients
                    closely and urge them to eat.
                    When the meal Is finished the patients
                    arise. Hefore they leave the room
                    the knives and forks are counted to
                    make sure that none are carried away.
                    When this is done the patients are
                    inarched back to the parlors.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1906-05-05/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=ABUSE+ASYLUM</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Mr Burroughs claimed that he saw
                    R an employe of the aamdry strike patients with his flat
                    beat them with towels and pillow cases oar the head and then put them
                    through the wringing out process
                    Herbert Spencer when he went on the
                    stand testified under oath that he saw
                    NktientE strapped te beds in Howard
                    Sail the steeping apartments of the
                    nomattal sw them placed fct strait-
                    Jackets sad teadcuffed Ha said that
                    the patterns xRes toR when strappedto
                    bed radical pain
                    The patients were strapped head and toot sad in such a position that they could not move He asserted that
                    he saw De Sales Lyons a colored
                    of the laundry wring out patients
                    and otherwise punish them In adtaaraceful
                    way
                    The pushing car method of punish
                    lair employes was administered by Sill
                    lard Sidney an employe of the laundry
                    On croes caranetfon lie said that he
                    only saw one patient strapped in bed
                    and only one placed In a straitjacket
                    though he noticed that there were
                    straitjaekets in the laundry
                    they having been sent there to be
                    The most pointed statements were
                    made bjr T L MeMurray who said
                    that he iron employed in the laundry
                    for four and a half years The
                    under oath stated that he saw
                    air SatterfieM tower and otherwise
                    punish Alphonso Rollins a number o
                    times On one occasion he saw Satter
                    field knock Rollns down and choke him
                    He said he saw several other patients
                    maltreated by Ute wrtngnso and
                    pushingear system He said that he
                    saw Foreman Maenche drunk on
                    occasions and in condition unfit
                    for the performance of his duties
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025661/1840-11-18/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=asylum+lunatic</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    We have had
                    1 puients recover," who, had made.
                    ; roverrierit the "first yea f.,' One 'pa-- .
                    '
                    w;i s b ro u ghl ' to t h e asy 1 Um i n Jn n e,
                    o. nr (iiiu ut'CD insane iwo years,
                    duririg the last' several months was
                    ialent ps to b: caged and chained. ooii
                    a3 he was placed in th asylum.
                    r,i3 pat under, a reqruUr coarse of
                    ! merit, bat no radical clnnge xccured
                    the first two years of his' residence
                    lis place.'" w J unci 1810, he was" a ly
                    in ihach the state'of mind as' he
                    ,it the time of his admission, although
                    !.ab"as had ; improved Soon af;er h'
                    n to improve, and in September he
                    disch.irg.'d entirely well. Had he
                    i removed al tfle end of six-month- as
                    sualfy the'ease, 'and been returned, to
                    former' cage, he would jindoultedly
                    e rem lined insane through life. This,
                    other f.icls, prove that old "cases are
                    necessarily incurableand that-eom- e
                    er under the most discouraging cir- -
                    'ance?; therefore a reasonable trial
                    1 i i . . .
                    1 ma.se itn them.,
                    --Duiing ihis lime two hundred and
                    ihirty-nin- e patien'shave received the benefits
                    of the asylum. Among1 these we
                    have hnd patients " manifesting every condition
                    of insanity, from the lowest state of
                    imbecility, by which he is incapable of attending
                    even to the wants of life, to the
                    violent and furious madman, ,: who, reckless
                    of consequences,- - exposes himself lo
                    all the dangers which are connected with
                    such a state. And worst of all, we have
                    had those suicidal ca?es, seeking every opportunity
                    of self-destructio- n,
                    , which an excited
                    and diseased imagination could in
                    vent.1 Nolwfthstandnig al! the dangers and
                    accidents to which, we have; been exposed,
                    nO'patlent has died from suicide, or accidental
                    injury. '. "'
                    T
                    , :.'.'. There are provided at the asylum, the '
                    usual means for amusements ; and exer-fcis- .'.
                    Bul the best moral means we have
                    found for the benefit of the patients,' is use-f- u
                    1 - employment ' 'in 1 the ope.n . air.; , Employment
                    on the farm' has contributed very
                    much to the promotion of the health
                    and recovery t our male patients. . It.re-- .
                    Iievesthe irksomeness. of confinement,
                    makes them pleasant' and cheerful, j'm- -
                    proves their! health, and promotes their recovery.!
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1908-08-02/ed-1/?sp=40&amp;q=asylum+lunatic</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn96088376/1908-01-31/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=asylum+ASYLUM+Asylum+Death+death+DEATHS</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Within my recollection several attendants
                    have contracted tuberculosis
                    and died. Whetheror not these
                    deaths were due to Improper conditions
                    at the asylum- - It Is Impossible
                    to say as the same persons might
                    havs contracted it had they resided
                    elsewhere.
                    The asylum Is always crowded and
                    considering present conditions, th
                    work along thla line during th past
                    year deserves commendation. Much
                    remains to be done, however, before
                    th medical staff 1 properly equipped
                    to prevent th ravages of thla
                    terrible malady.
                    I found no laboratory or pathologic
                    apparatus ot any kind but th superintendent.
                    Dr. Stelner. told me that
                    practical working outfit had been ordered
                    and would be Installed and put
                    Into us at the earliest possible date.
                    ' The Ideal way to handle th tuberculosis
                    cases at th asylum would b
                    In cottages apart from th main
                    building; thla would involve a considerable
                    expenditure of money both for
                    first cost and maintenance and
                    would hardly meet the approval of
                    the average legislator. A much leas
                    expensive plan and - one efficient,
                    would be to construct open air pavilions
                    adjoining the infirmary.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn97065122/1920-07-24/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Asylum+death</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/moldovan-collection-at-the-library-of-congress/about-moldova</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/french-collections/books-france</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-asylums/introduction</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/latinx-civil-rights/cuban-adjustment-act</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026965/1887-10-20/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1789&amp;index=8&amp;date2=1924&amp;searchType=advanced&amp;language=&amp;sequence=1&amp;words=Blackwell+bly+Island+Nellie&amp;proxdistance=5&amp;rows=20&amp;ortext=&amp;proxtext=&amp;phrasetext=Blackwells+Island&amp;andtext=Nellie+Bly&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
        </results>
    </topic>
    <topic>
        <!--This XML file contains the results of the Chronicling American april fools origin.
        It includes 10 pre-selected articles and 5 query-based results, with relevance judgments and excerpts.
        -->
        <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-april-fools</id>
        <results>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85034039/1871-04-21/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+fools+pranks&amp;r=0.339,0.401,0.698,0.408,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026994/1873-04-01/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=april+pranks+fools</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    The origin or "April Fool" ia as remote
                    aod as impossible to determine as the birth¬
                    day of the first fool who marred Nature's
                    original design of intellectual Man. We
                    trace it everywhere; but the Beeret hour of
                    its birth bafiles research. We are forced to
                    admit its existence, without being able to
                    assign a cause. The Romans undoubtedly
                    enjoyed its questionable fun. They cer¬
                    tainly carried its memory in all their con¬
                    quests. Its observance was long cherished
                    among numeróos nations. Abandoned to
                    the yalgar in our self-elected age of extreme
                    refinement,
                    using itself as a trowel to cement tbe crum ti¬
                    ling Kellogg platform ; striking the first
                    blow lo insure its own annihilation. April
                    Fool I Louisiana issalog addresses and
                    sending representatives to the Union at
                    large, convinced that her distress must be
                    of National in ten ;t. April Fool 1
                    Amadeos accepting the Spanish Grown'
                    which bas so loog been unsettled that ils
                    balance cac not be determined; giving a
                    gratuitous kick to accelerate ita certain fall.
                    April Fooll Spanish Cortes insisting OD
                    the recognition "de facto'? of a republic
                    which does not exist "de jure;" selling op
                    a ten-pio Republic for ihe mero sport of
                    bowling it down. April Fool !
                    England's tories and whigs doing their
                    best to destroy the ablest minister of the
                    Crown on the question of the Irish Univer¬
                    sity; paying tilhes of "mint, annis and
                    "cummin" while neglecting the weightier
                    matters of tbe law. April Fool !
                    France with Thiers more iban king, shoot¬
                    ing itself hoarse wilh "Vive la République 1
                    "A bas l'Empire I A bas la monarchie I"
                    April Fool !
                    Ukraine peasants revolting against an
                    îutocrat who owns half the Continent of
                    Surope; ramming themselves lalo monars"
                    br the mere chance of being discharged at
                    heir masters' heads. April Fool !
                    Each nation convinced that "the Parlia-
                    "mentof Man, and Federation of the world"
                    s to be convoked ander its own vine and tig
                    :ree. April Fool 1
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014635/1894-04-01/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=april+fools+pranks&amp;r=-0.297,0.166,1.638,0.956,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-04-02/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=april+fool+pranks&amp;r=-0.79,-0.195,2.58,1.506,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1900-04-01/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=april+fool+pranks&amp;r=-0.765,-0.101,2.529,1.477,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Wlatlon to each other.
                    A learned antiquary, writing in 1599,
                    claims that our AprilFools' day Is but a
                    continuation of the Qulrinalla, or feast of
                    fools, bf the ancient Romans. In-"The
                    British Apollo." a most ingenious work
                    published !n 17C8.
                    ""Whence proceeds the custom of making
                    April fools? Answer: From a memorable
                    transaction happening between
                    " the
                    Romans and the Sabine.3, mentioned by
                    Dionysius. Which was thus: The Romans,
                    about the Infancy of their city, wanting
                    wives, and finding they could not obtain
                    the neighboring women by their peaceable
                    addresses, resolved to make use of stratagem,
                    and accordingly Romulus instituted
                    certain games to be performed in the beginning
                    of April(according to the Roman
                    calendar) in honor of Neptune. Upon notice
                    thereof the bordqring Inhabitants,
                    with their whole families, flocked to Rome
                    to see this mighty celebration, whereupon
                    the Romans seized a number of the Sablna
                    virgins and ravished them, which imposition,
                    we suppose, may be the foundation
                    of this foolish custom." This most absurd
                    and wholly unjustifiable account of the
                    origin of making April fools is thus ridiculed
                    by a poet of the time:
                    Some old folk-writers claim that our
                    AprilFool customs are attributable to the
                    fact that the year formerly began, as to
                    come purposes and in some respects, on
                    the 25th of March, which was supposed
                    ?o be the day of Our Lord's incarnation.
                    At that time' it was customary for all
                    festivals to continue for an octave, or period of eight days. April1 Is the
                    octave of March 25, and the last day
                    of a festival octavo was always marked
                    by the greatest abandon and festivity.
                    At the New Year season especially all
                    sorts of wild, mirthful pranks were Indulged
                    In, and of these Itis believed that
                    our April fool usages - were a part.
                    Origins of a religious nature have been
                    boldly claimed for April Fools' day by
                    many writers. An old English antiquary,
                    writingIn1753. states that the custom of
                    imposing upon and ridiculing people on
                    the Ist of Aprilmay have an allusion to
                    the mockery of the Savior of the world
                    by the Jews. Something like that which
                    we call making April fools Is practiced
                    also abroad in Catholic countries on Innocents'
                    day, on which occasion people
                    run through all the rooms, making a pretended
                    search in and under the beds. In
                    memory, Ibelieve, of the search made by
                    Herod for the discovery and the destruction
                    of the child Jesus and of his having
                    been imposed upon and deceived by the
                    wise men, who, contrary to his orders
                    and expectation, "returned to their own
                    country another way.
                    When the early Britons were Induced to
                    forsake' their Druidical priests and Idols
                    and to embrace Christianity, It was their
                    custom" for many years after to annually
                    hold in their churches at the commencement
                    of April a great festival, resembling
                    the Roman Saturnalia, at which
                    they indulged in a thousand ridiculous
                    and indecent ceremonies, gambols and
                    dancing grotesquely to ludicrous anthems.
                    These singular observances referred to the
                    exploded pretensions of the Druids, whom
                    this
                    '
                    festival was designed to hold up to
                    scorn and derision. That there Is no more
                    effective weapon than ridicule was again
                    proved In this case, for this feast of fools
                    the heathen religion and its priests than
                    all the collateral aids of fire and sword,
                    though they were also freely employed.
                    The continuance of customs? especially
                    droll ones, which suit the gross taste of
                    the masses? after the original cause of
                    them has been removed. Is a very common
                    occurence. and by many antiquaries It is
                    firmly believed that "fooling" people on
                    the Ist of Aprilis simply a perpetuation
                    of the annual public ridiculing of the old
                    Druid's and their superstitions.
                    Still another oripin. of a semi-religious
                    character, 13 thus claimed for AprilFools'
                    day In a quaint old book of folk-lore called "Father Time's Flyghtes." published
                    in London In 1659. "numerous Jewish Origin of the Custom of Making
                    Fools on the First of April. This is said
                    to have begun from "ye mistake of Noah sending ye dove out before ye water had
                    abated, on ye first day of ye month which
                    among ye Hebrews answers to our first
                    of April,and to perpetrate ye memory of
                    this deliverance it was thought proper
                    whoever forgot so remarkable a circumstance
                    to punish them by sending them upon some fool's errand similar to- the
                    Ineffectual message upon which ye bird was sent by ye patriarch."
                    The French associate with the first of Aprilprecisely the same Ideas as do Enr llsh speaking nations, but the person Im- posed upon, whom we call an April FcJ*. they style an AprilFl3h or Polsson d' -vril.
                    In the "Etymology of French proverbs,"
                    a most curious and delightful
                    work published In 1356. Billlngton Ithe
                    author, gives the following expiation
                    of the origin of AprilFool customs / "The
                    word poisson is corrupted throtffn the
                    Ignorance of the people from pasr'on. and length of time has almost totall- defaced
                    the original intention, which w^ as follows:
                    That as the Passion of c-n* Saviour
                    took place about this time o'the year,
                    and as the Jews sent Chris*; backward
                    and forward to mock and't->rment him.
                    1. c., from Annns to Caiaph?*». from Caiaphas
                    to Pilate, from Pilate -°- Herod and
                    from Herod back to Pilate, this ridiculous
                    or rather Impious custorrAook Its rise
                    from thence, by which we send about
                    from one place to anoO«r such persona
                    aa we think proper subjects of our ridicule."
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085187/1909-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+fools+pranks&amp;r=-0.802,0.103,2.604,1.52,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-04-02/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+fools+pranks</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066313/1915-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+foolls+prank&amp;r=-1.244,-0.018,3.489,1.628,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    According io me map wmcu
                    U p Wrench has prepared and kept
                    In the corridor of the third floor of
                    Academic Hall, European armies have
                    made radical changes in their maneuvers.
                    The French apparently have
                    given up the war and have fled to the
                    western coast of France. The English
                    have disappeared entirely. All
                    the German forces of the western
                    theater are quartered in Paris. In the
                    east, the Austrian and German forces
                    are massed in the lowlands of Prussia,
                    surrounded by Russian and Ser
                    vian troops. A few Servians are left
                    as garrisons along the frontier. One
                    lone Austrian army corps has escaped
                    and is now stationed in the middle of
                    the North Sea.
                    The havoc Is attributed to some
                    April Fool prank.
                    Another Instance of April Fool
                    thoughtfulness was shown this morning
                    when a member of the Agricultural
                    faculty phoned to the county
                    jail asking "who had left a call for
                    him."
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88084272/1916-04-01/ed-1/?sp=14&amp;q=april+fools+parks&amp;r=-0.811,-0.046,2.621,1.224,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058393/1922-04-01/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=april+fools+pranks</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/concerts-pick-of-the-week/april-2020/week-of-april-6</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/concerts-pick-of-the-week/april-2020</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/concerts-pick-of-the-week/april-2021/week-of-april-30</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-admin-abraham-lincoln-assassination/introduction</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-spanish-american-war/introduction</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
        </results>
    </topic>
    <topic>
        <!--This XML file contains the results of the Chronicling American typhoid mary.
        It includes 10 pre-selected articles and 5 query-based results, with relevance judgments and excerpts.
        -->
        <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-typhoid-mary</id>
        <results>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1907-04-01/ed-1/seq-3/#words=typhoid+TYPHOID+Marie+Mary+Marys</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    When Mary was taken to the Hoard
                    of Health reception hospital for examination
                    ¬
                    I
                    U required the persuasion of r
                    lull a dozen health Inspectors to carry
                    her there Then II was found that accommodations
                    ¬
                    were cramped There
                    sons no room large enough to hold the
                    cook and the doctors ivlio were ksslrnedIn Inspvot her Thereupon ahe was removed
                    ¬
                    o n private room In Iloostvclt
                    Hospital where ahe now IsDr William II 1ark and Dr HrmanIJI r germ jPdalUt have UkejLrlturre 1f the race They believe they
                    will have to call In other gem experts
                    Id nub them In IntcatlRatlnc the
                    sourea of Marys germ supply Her
                    Case Is absolutely Dnlque lo medical
                    liUlury
                    According to Dr Park and Dr Wag
                    wfio have tentatively xamln t MUsllverson ilia Is In complet poe esslon
                    of a million or more germs none nt
                    which howrver San dot her the hart
                    harm She Is ummune though tv1th every
                    breath she ttkehrt draws In sal
                    exhales u loud ot dreaded bacilli
                    The
                    >
                    woman was stricken with the dlsj
                    ease bout six years ago and recovered
                    after the attack jftd run lie uunl course
                    and was declared cured It now appears
                    ¬
                    says Dr bowel that her Intestinal
                    ¬
                    tract has contlnuoj o produceand develop typhoid germs which carried
                    ¬
                    the malady to others lr Ben
                    sej says she Is a living tower factory
                    This Is all the more skngulsr When
                    considered with the slateaient that she
                    Is well and hearty And i hows not the
                    slightest attr-aof tsklng jtyphoW
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1907-04-07/ed-1/seq-12/#words=Typhoid+typhoid+Oyster+Bay</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Though in possession of a million or more
                    germs Miss Ilvereon save an Interesting
                    exhibition of her physical prowess when
                    requested to appear at the hospital for
                    examination the Iwmblned efforts of live
                    attendants being required to land her in
                    that institution
                    When inquiry oonCwnlng his place of
                    refuge in the event of the cooks release
                    was made by Dr L O Howard Dr Soper
                    answered briefly Europe The hospital
                    authorities have promised to Inform me
                    immediately upon her release
                    Miss Ilverson is forty years old tall of
                    good figure and apparently in perfect
                    health She tats resolutely refused to
                    submit tranquilly to expert efforts to
                    locate the germs she is alleged to give
                    oft or relate any details of her put his
                    tory As the result however of investigations covering ten years of her past life
                    Dr Soper said that in four families In
                    which she was employed there were as
                    many epidemics of typhoid fover result
                    lop in the illness of twontysix persons
                    and one death
                    Soper I was called upon to Investigatean outbreak of typhoid fever in a familyin Oyster Bay N Y afx out of eleven of
                    whom were stricken with the disease An
                    exhaustive examination was made of the
                    previous history of the patients of the
                    members of that and other households in
                    the neighborhood and of the water and
                    food supply the results being unsatisfactory In every Instance My suspicions be
                    ing directed toward the cook 1 questioned
                    her but she refused to speak concerning
                    herself and although every inducement
                    was offered she declined to commit herself with regard to her past life Then
                    U was I began an investigation which
                    disclosed the fact that in three other
                    families in which she was employed her
                    arrival after a period of ten days to two
                    monta resulting in the appearance of
                    typhoid
                    The majority of the patients were
                    servants of the various households the
                    Desk remaining an immune in each Instance Site denied ever having bad a
                    serious attack of typhoid but is said to
                    have made the statement that site at one
                    time had a mild attack The problem now
                    confronting the authorities is what Is to
                    be done with her An operation would
                    result in destroying her activities as
                    bacilli carrier but to this she will not
                    give her consent As it is she is regarded
                    as a menace to public health
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1909-07-04/ed-1/seq-47/#words=typhoid+cook+cooks+Typhoid</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Epidemics or typhoid, diphtheria, cholera and
                    £**\u25a0**? are largely due to innocent and healthy
                    "ctavej-ers." who are a greater menace to any
                    KSarsEity than bomb throwers and Black Hand
                    irtSsts.
                    • Ittaigfcl b- tlijfhUyuseful to warn the germ
                    f-JJf™ whose suspicion or their state has been iSSW b> bacteriological examination. They
                    t«k^U artful for a while not to lafect others. it?"2*2*™*
                    Precautions an washing their haeds
                    \u25a0\u25a0\u25a0 ao *a* bal this would act last lor-C- Tliey would .*
                    *
                    i«** aad would relax precautions. Itis not
                    Hr~*a tuti to look after the welfare of others
                    »~tn 701
                    *°*a *
                    Jfar
                    *ta not at aU concerned. It
                    ccl^f t*»»t tne danger is much greater in some oci« 2Hm' _ i"***
                    |R o«hers-ln a cook, for example,
                    *!*|
                    T' MsJlor.. A cook handles food, and
                    I—.
                    ®Maßji mawara germs to her victims. A
                    rocia r~'* woixW **.comparatively safe, but we
                    eot bete' 1
                    '"
                    *
                    onipel him to stick to that trade and
                    la
                    *
                    ***\u25a0*« a cook. The supervision of occupations •^
                    £
                    :er'
                    « Prcgramme."
                    SomeUmes a surgical opera- * SB^rf i!
                    "•*"\u25a0•«\u25a0 «* Urn gall Madder, which ls
                    i««ae*r t:
                    r
                    '**
                    Cdil1
                    *
                    l
                    '
                    i
                    *c*
                    of rticrobea. effects a
                    crsz „
                    *''
                    ra* *****
                    °*«> tried, but Ifear that a
                    of =n i
                    s ***\u25a0•» to killthe germs in the body
                    Vj-Eh!iT?"*1 -vb>*ct woui kill the subject, too.
                    **"»Tea
                    '• lever and tuberculosis are our worst contin, "**\u25a0«?• Tii*lr perms roa^ thrive And mul-
                    »"«aua«r l
                    ,
                    "***\u25a0•
                    1 v;rulcnoe 1:1 the systems of
                    *^swii!T. mm*ny y
                    **arr' The
                    **
                    ... o'l***'I***1*** or the patient.
                    "Th» intestinal mucous membrane supports a rich
                    and varied bacterial flora, among which are several
                    potentially harmful species, and sometimes, even
                    under conditions of health, the bacilli of typhoid
                    fever, cf dysentery and in regions In which cholera
                    is endemic or during its epidemics, at cholera."
                    Dr. Thomas S. Southworth. In a paper pond hefore the eighteenth annual meeting of the American
                    Pedlatric Society, told of a Brooklyn youngster under two years of age. and not known to have typhoid, who gave fatal ilos*- of the disease to bat
                    mother. Infected two Misters and th» being taken
                    to live with a New York family, communicated the !
                    disease to three children of that family. The Infan- j
                    tile typhoid carrier was finally tak«*n to ihospital
                    and a specimen of his blood was reported by the i
                    Health Department to show "a positive Widal reaction, thus proving him to have had typhoid fever
                    at some time in the past."
                    -
                    Dr. Bouthworth said: «•
                    ••Since th« establishment of the Royal restitu- j
                    tions for BacterloloEici.l Research, arb'^a have
                    taken up the .study and control of typhoid In \u25a0••:\u25a0\u25a0
                    tain districts of Germany, evidence la rapidly appearing of the spread of tyajnoid by persons ion?
                    convalescent, who are now technically spoken of
                    as 'bacillus carriers.' These are defined as those
                    whose «xcreta contain the bacilli after ten weeks
                    trosß th beginning of the illness, or from the beginning of the last relapse. Unit,at Trier, discovered twenty-two typhoid carriers; to seven of
                    whom other cases, often multiple, were traced. A.
                    Besserer and J. Jaffe found typhoid bacilli from
                    four persons who had had typhoid thr«-e months,
                    six months, four years and seven years previously.
                    Sfeig*-. also, who states that 'contact infection' from
                    these cases Is coming more and more into prominence, reports two especially interesting cases in
                    Which mother* having ••«•" typhoid and livingthereafter under circumstances which apparently precluded reinfection. Infected their children two yearn ;
                    and ten years later
                    . The infectious character of many urines dur- •
                    Ing convalescence from typhoid Is well established.
                    Many Investigators have worked in this field. Thus .
                    far it would appear that typhoid bacilli may be !
                    found In about a per cent of the cases. .. •
                    '
                    RJcnardsou's conservative statement is that they
                    may persist for weeks, occasionally for months.
                    rarely for years. . . . 'When present, the bacilli
                    are usually In pure culture and enormous numbers.
                    Petruschky. previously Quoted, estimated them in ;
                    one case to be 172.000.000 in one cubic centimetre." '
                    These bacilli also persist in pus for a
                    year or j
                    more, and In the sputum of patients having a com- I
                    plicating bronchitis or pneumonia. Seven weeks Is
                    the. longest period recorded in the latter case. •
                    ItIs stated that typhoid carriers may give the disease by coughing and sneezing. Bom* e«rtns are
                    found In perspiration, European observers discovered that 3 p«r cent of 1,785 cases examined were
                    typhoid carriers
                    Having exhausted all his clews, the baffled mrdl- !
                    cal detective doubtless felt like putting up the
                    mystery to old-fashioned Providence. However,-
                    his investigations had established one thing—
                    common cause for the common result. He began to ;
                    meditate upon a seemingly trivial fact— that the j
                    family had, changed cooks on August 4. An ordi- .
                    nary physician while conceding that a change
                    of cooks might cause nervous prostration, would
                    not have- dreamed that it might cause an epidemic
                    of typhoid fever. But Dr. Soper was just then
                    keen on Insignificant and even absurd details. He
                    reflected on the fact that about three weeks before .
                    the typhoid epidemic broke out an old family cook ]
                    had been discharged and replaced by a new one, of ,
                    whom little was known. She was hired through an i
                    employment bure-u and stayed but a short time. |
                    leaving some three weeks after the outbreak of
                    typhoid. She wra a tall Irish woman of about
                    forty. in seemingly good health, and her name
                    was Mary Mallon.
                    to tell her history or to permit an examination. The physician
                    nevertheless obtained her history and found all his
                    suspicions amply conririm-d. Cases of typhoid had
                    occurred In seven out of tight families in which
                    st. had worked in the test ten years.
                    The first reecrd of Marys Involuntary devastation was in 1900, when the was employed in the
                    sunrmer home «.»f a New Yorker at Mamaroneck,
                    N. V. A young man visitor to the family was attacked with typhoid in September, and it was
                    thought he got it from a previous visit to the soJdk'r.H* camp at Montuuk Point. Long Island. But
                    slrce the pati»>nt had lived In the Mamaroneck
                    nous* at least ten days after visiting the camp, he
                    could not have contracted the disease from the
                    sbldicrw. * Mary, the rook, left within ,ifew days
                    after the development of this case. She had bean
                    in the family fcr three years, without apparently
                    \u25a0being connected with typhoid.
                    In1902 a Ken V« rk lawyrr,with four members of
                    his family and five servants^ went la Dark Harbor. Mi. for the summer. Seren persons wen soon
                    ill with typhoid. tUbm a trained nurse succumbed and also a woman *«J day*, work in thp
                    house. The only persons who escaped were the
                    ec«.k-Mary Alallon-aml the lawyer, who had had
                    typhoid Boma-Yyears before. Well known medical
                    men vainly puzzled over this case. The drinking
                    water, obtained J'roru a spring, whs. analysed by
                    Chemists In Boston and Now York and pronounced
                    pure. There were no other crises of typhoid in the
                    neighborhood. The house was "••« and it couldn't
                    be rented after \u25a0\u25a0\u25a0\u25a0 outbreak,
                    woman be taken into custody by the department and examined bacterlologlcally on the
                    ground that she wiu a perambulating disease. She
                    refused a voluntary examination, \u25a0whereupon the
                    department had her removed to the detention hospital on March 19. "after a severe struggle, in
                    which she showed remarkable bodily strength and
                    agiilty"
                    A bacteriological examination showed the
                    continuous presence af numberless millions of
                    typhoid bacilli in her system and her blood gave
                    the positive Wldal reaction. .
                    Thus the champion typhoid carrier was captured
                    and exiled to North Brother Island-and the department does not want to look up the others .ike
                    her for fear that it would take 'several islands to
                    hold them all.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84025841/1909-07-10/ed-1/seq-7/#words=TYPHOID+MARY</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    woman. Khn is known to the
                    i departrafat as Typl
                    red throogh her lawyer that ahe
                    was Uteajally deatirea] of her iu.-
                    In r applit ation th*
                    health raaaartaflaal alleged that Mary
                    hat] I wlth whom she eamo ln t
                    while hrrself immune. she had tho
                    power of comrnunlcatinjr typhohl fr-vt r
                    to otii. rs involuntarilv. »- The tt.ok statetl that she ha.'
                    treatetl on Ntirth Brotl 1 like
                    a l per and h:t tooeI aay u ** '
                    bt r onb
                    Baa
                    I>r William H Parks. of the health
                    department. aay* that Mary ia
                    than two aeore pereoaa in this
                    country who are known aa t ba lili t-arr:. r« and that her raae la
                    all.
                    Tt.. (4 BBfl BT4 BBBSM !jre ln
                    ¦all hladder and to
                    from there hy the htle M^-hi.
                    Bew grrms are takitiR the pl»
                    at are oarrivd av. .
                        The experl ry effort haa been made to cure Mary. who
                        ls a remarkably healthy looklng wo¬
                    man. but. aciordinv arka. wlth¬
                    out avall H ea that. unleaa
                    Bhe court ordera otlurwis.. ahe will
                    hare to remain on N'orth H
                    Island all her life.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1909-07-19/ed-1/seq-4/#words=Typhoid+typhoid+Mary</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    This is the cafe of
                    Mary Mallon, a competent domestic and
                    blameless woman, who appears Jikely toendure
                    perpetual confinement and isolation because,
                    althougl-r herself perfectly healthy, she appears
                    to carry typhoid infection wherever she goes.
                    In the/ New York supreme court Justice
                    Jinanger Saturday ruled that the risk of discharging Mary Mallon
                    from the Riverside hospital is too great for,the court to assume. It
                    is believeil that she harbors typhoid germs in her: person and is consequently unsafe to be at large. C
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88077573/1910-02-21/ed-1/seq-2/#words=TYPHOID+Typhoid+typhoid+MARY+Mary</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    Now York, Fob. 21. Mary Mallon,
                    flippantly referred to an "Typhoid
                    Mary," was reloased from quarantine on North Brother Island by order
                    of tho health department, with tho
                    provision that Bho Is not to Beek employment as a servant In this city.
                    For. the last threo yearn Mary has
                    lived Bccluded in a lonely hut on the-
                    -
                    Island becnupe, according to nhyjjp.
                    clahs, sho Is tho victim of ri peculiar'
                    Btato of nffnlrs. Medical men say
                    thnt although Mary has nover suffered from typhoid fever, bacilli of
                    tho typhus variety Just dote erf her
                    system an an abiding placo, and that
                    therefore) she Ih a'anurco of danger to
                    persons in each houso whore she
                    lived.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038615/1911-12-04/ed-1/seq-2/#words=TYPHOID+Typhoid+typhoid+MARY+Mary</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    "Typhoid
                    Mary," the cook who came by that
                    nickname because of the cases of ty¬
                    phoid fever tnat seemed to follow her
                    around from family to family, Is about
                    to Bue tho city and Its Health Depart¬
                    ment for $60,000 damugos for keeping
                    her In conllnement on North Brother
                    Island for three years.
                    Papors will be served within the
                    next fow days on Dr. Ixiderle, head of
                    the Health Department, and four
                    physicians, Dr. Durlington, Dr. Super,
                    Dr. Purk and Dr. Westmorelund. Mury Mallon Is the name on the complaint.
                    She Is forty years old, and says she has
                    never had typhoid fever or any other
                    dangerous diseusc. She was released
                    from the hospital last February, and
                    since that time she has been unable to
                    follow her trade of cooking, and her
                    chances of making a living have been
                    greatly reduced, she asserts. She will
                    attempt to show that she was not tho
                    typhoid germ carrier the city nut hurt¬
                    les have made hor out.
                    Tho lawyer who will prosecute
                    Mary's case against, the city is the
                    same ono who appeared for her before
                    the Supreme Court In 11)03. when her
                    freedom was denied. He is George
                    Francis O'Nell, of 5 Beekman Street,
                    and Is a specialist In medico-legal
                    questions.
                    "If the Board of Health," he said,
                    "is going to send every cook to Jail
                    ¦who happens to come under their des¬
                    ignation of 'germ carrier,' It won't be
                    long before we havo no cooks left,'and
                    the domestic problem will be further
                    complicated. What would the poor
                    Jokcsmlth do then for his stories about
                    the cook who >ulos tho house?"
                    He began to look for some peculiar situation., and focussed his suspicions on tho faet that the family had changed cooks about three weeks before the fever began. Dr. Soper then began to investigate tho record of Mary Mullon. He found that In 1001 she had been employed at
                    the homo of Henry Gllsey at Hands
                    Point, U I. The family had eleven
                    persons In It. of whom seven wero
                    servants. Within a month four of the
                    servants were taken with typhoid.
                    In 1002 Mary was the cook for J.
                    Coloman Druyton at Dark Harbor, Mo.
                    Seven persons out of nine were taken
                    111 within a short time. Three other
                    Instances are set forth where the fever
                    followed within a «hört period after
                    the employment of the cook. In all, he laid at her door twenty-six cases
                    of typhoid. And he ndded that he had
                    traced but fragments of her history
                    during ten years.
                    The physicians of the Health De¬
                    partment have never been able to dis¬
                    cover that Mary herself ever had
                    typhoid. Sho Is described as a robust
                    woman, and weighing about 190
                    pounds The doctor suggested that
                    she undergo en operation. To this sho
                    would not submit. In fact, she always
                    Instated that she never gavo typhoid to
                    anybody, but that the wuter was at
                    fault.
                    The case was adjudged one for con¬
                    finement In March, 1907, and Mary,
                    after a contost of physical strength
                    with five policemen, was taken to
                    North Brother Island. In 1909 she was
                    before iho Supreme Court on a writ of
                    habeas corpus. Judge Olegerleh sent
                    her back to tho hospital, expressing
                    sympathy for the woman, but Insisting
                    that she was a menace to tho com¬
                    munity.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1912-12-31/ed-1/seq-4/#words=TYPHOID+Typhoid+typhoid+MARY+Mary</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    om her.
                    The case of Typhoid Mary ib tea bark to
                    1 105. when an epidemic of typhoid fever
                    luokc out In ()stcr Hay. Six In a family
                    were sttlcken The w ater supply was found
                    to be all light and nothing was wrong with
                    the food. Mary .Mnilnn was cooli He-fothat she hud been cook In the household of llemy Gllsey at Hands Point, L. I.,
                    in liiOI. Within four weeks of her ap
                    pliance ns a sotvant In the latter house
                    four other servant were sick from
                    typhoid.
                    Two years previously Typhoid Mary had
                    worked In the summer home of ,1 Coleman
                    Drayton at Dark Harbor, Me. Seen person out of nine' In the household were
                    Lilian ill with typhoid and two others, a
                    trained nurse ami a woman who cai. i In
                    to woik by the day. were attacked. Sev
                    eral other cases wetc traced to Mary Mai
                    Ion
                    The Itoaid of Health sent her to North
                    Brother Island III 1907 and she was kept
                    there for two and n half yearn Then Mr.
                    O'Neill obtained her release through court
                    proceedings.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88085187/1915-04-06/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Typhoid+Mary</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    typhoid germs!
                    Her Own Caldron.
                    The twentieth century witch—
                    "Typhoid Mary" Mallon—is upto-date with a vengeance! Legendary witches of old used to
                    build red fires under ugly cauldrons and brew deadly potions.
                    But poor "Typhoid Mary"
                    Mallon—all unwillingly how- ever—uses far more scientific and more fateful magic.
                    Hlie requires no cauldron—
                    she manufactures WITHIN
                    lIKKSKI.F the evil potions
                    which she spreads about the community. She Is constantly producing millions of virulent typhoid fever germs!
                    Taken to Isolated Hut.
                    Five years ago she was isolated
                    by the New York health authorl:
                    ties. She was released on a promise to remain constantly un- der surveillance, but she broke
                    away, and caused several new epidemics In the space of 10
                    years! Though perfectly
                    '
                    well herself, "Typhoid Mary"
                    had produced up to that
                    time at least 580 serious case*
                    of typhoid fever, several of
                    which were fatal.
                    outbreaks of typhoid before she was again captured.
                    NOW the health department
                    has decided to take drastic meas- ures. "Typhoid Mary" has been
                    secretly conveyed to a brick hut on North Brother island, a bleak
                    piece of land way up the East
                    river far above Hell Gate.
                    In the fall of 1906 a mysterious outbreak of typhoid had oc- curred In the summer cottage
                    rented by a New York banker on Long Island. Six persons ln his
                    family were taken with tbe dis- ease.
                    After a dozen experts had
                    failed to account forthe epidemic
                    they called Dr. George A. Soper,
                    famous sanitary engineer, who
                    had had charge of cleaning up
                    Galveston after the flood, when,
                    in his own words. "8,000 bodies
                    lay festering in the sun."
                    Isolated Once Before.
                    It took four months of hard
                    detective work before Dr. Soper
                    discovered the source of the epidemic— which was "Typhoid
                    Mary" Mallon!
                    - She had been cook ln the family that summer.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045389/1915-07-11/ed-1/seq-42/#word=Typhoid+Mary+germs+Microbe</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    oman refused to keep her hands clean.
                    in another Instance four cases of typhoid were
                    traced to a typhoid carrier who had had the disease
                    forty years before. Think of ltt Forty years before I
                    Then there was the manager of an estate who was
                    found to be a typhoid carrier. This man had suffered
                    from typhoid ten years before. And during those ten
                    years there had been sixteen cases of the disease on or
                    near the estate- It was practically certain this man¬
                    ager had been the source of those cases.
                    put over on the science
                    of preventive medicine. TIiIb was the typhoid
                    earriei^-a person who may or may not have bad
                    typhoid fever; a person, Indeed, apparently In perfect
                    health, -who could harbor the germs of typhoid fever
                    and Infect other people with them.
                    A baker's apprentice.this was in southwest Ger¬
                    many.died of typhoid fever. Then the doctor set to
                    Jgurlng out how this patient had got his fever. Here
                    we must understand that typhoid la, like cholera and
                    dysentery, an "Ingestion Infection'*.that Is, the only
                    way you can get typhoid Is through having swallowed
                    ~
                    and drink that has contained the typhoid germs
                    Though typhoid la a general disease and affeots the
                    whole body, tho main parts affected are the 41s68ttre
                    organs and apparatus, especially the gall bladder and
                    the Intestines, in which the germs multiply and from
                    which the germs called also Che typhoid bacilli are
                    emitted.
                    Wei), on Investigation, it was found that this baker's
                    wife had typhoid some years before, since which Al¬
                    ness practically every one of that baker's apprentices
                    had come down with "some kind of digestive dis¬
                    turbance" soon after his apprenticeship began. An
                    examination of the baker's wife.all this was, of
                    course, several years after she had had typhoid.by
                    the health authorities resulted In the discovery that
                    ger had been the source of those cases.
                    Many milk-borne typhoid cases are due to typhoid bacillus carriers engaged in dairying.people working in that chain which has so many hidden links In its
                    course, from the cow, through the dairy, the milk
                    trains, the city handlers, the domestics, to the consinner's Upa As for Instance: A number of typhoid
                    eases occurred among employes at a particular dairy and among the consumers of that dairy's milk. Four¬
                    teen of those people were found to he typhoid carriers.
                    One of them, a woman employe at the dairy, had had
                    typhoid seventeen years before. Here was evidently the origin of the whole trouble. Drs. Bolduan and
                    Noble, of the New York City Health Department, some
                    three years ago discovered a typhoid carrier of forty- six years standing to whom a large outbreak In milkborne typhoid fever was traced
                    More women than men typhoid carriers have been traced. Possibly there sre not reslly more women thus affected. It may be there only appssr to be
                    tnofe, because the chief danger of euch infection lies In handling fobdstuffs, as by cooks and waitfesRee. Be¬ sides. women are more prone to gallstone diseases, and the gall bladder has been found the chief factory of typhoid germ production in the human body, although other parts of the digestive cankl manufacture them. Thus recently a woman typhoid carrier submitted to have her gill bladder operated on, and no typhoid
                    germs were found in that organ, and yet she was a
                    carrier of virulent typhoid germs. The German doo- tors, who are permitted by their Government to be much more thorough than we are, found that of 450 female typhoid carrier 314 were hausfrauen (persons who. handle food, cooks, boarding house k'eepers and
                    so on), while fifty-six were domestic seeyants.
                    It has been estimated that from 4 per cent up of typhoid fever sufferers continue to shed the typhoid bacilli for indeterminate periods. And there are other* who shed those germs who don't appear to have had
                    this Infection: say they have not had It; certainly have
                    not been abea on that account. First.The doctors make three classes of typhoid
                    ease
                    carriers.
                    and continue
                    The acute carriers, who have had the dis¬ to discharge the germs not longer than six weeks after convalescence.that Is. after com¬
                    plete recovery.
                    Second, the chronic carriers, who may or may not have had'the dlsesae, but who keep on discharging the
                    germs Indefinitely. Those who have not had the dis¬
                    ease are called the symptomless cases, and they are
                    called lhtermediate carriers, or, as tho German doc¬
                    tors say.take a long breath here.the Typhusbaall- lenswischentraeger.
                    And, third, there are the temporary carriers, who
                    have never had typhoid at all, or who may have, per¬ haps, been "walking cases." but who discharge the
                    germs for a short period, then are free -of them for
                    a time and then again shed them. It has been com¬
                    puted that something like one in every thousand of
                    us Is a typhoid carrier, whether we have had tho disease or not.
                    Obviously, then, it Is a difficult proposition to pre¬ vent the spread of typhoid fever by the typhoid bacillus
                    carriers. Surgery, as we have seen, does not avail,
                    because other parts of the digestive tract than the gall bladder may contain tho germs, and one cannot have the' whole of bis internal organs removed and
                    live. Investigators with bacterial vaccines have had
                    some fair results, but far from good enough for such
                    means to be successfully or universally applied. There remains then the expedients of segregating the typhoid carrier, as Is done In the case of leprosy.
                    and, Indeed, the carrier is more of a menace than the leper.or, what In effect would be the same thing, to
                    force him into constant cleanliness or to restrict his
                    occupation in such a way as to bring his harm-makirig down to a minimum. This last expedient, as will be
                    seen later, is already in force iq some districts.
                    Against the efficacy of the segregation idea there can
                    be nothing urged. The great obstacle to carrying It
                    out Is. of course, a sentimental one, If we choose to so
                    designate the well nigh universal feeling that causes
                    for isolation of a man from his kind
                    ought not to be lightly multiplied
                    Such segregation Would be for most
                    carriers solitary Imprisonment for life.
                    But It would not be necessary to
                    confine typhoid carriers If they would
                    only understand and ofoserve the sim¬
                    ple precautions they should take
                    '
                    qrder that the health and lives
                    Others shall not be endangered
                    them. The activities of typhoid car¬
                    riers must be so restricted that they
                    shall neither Infect food nor their sur¬
                    roundings. In essence, all they have
                    to do Is to be careful about their
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/civil-war-soldiers/john-grimball</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-wright-brothers/introduction</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-wright-brothers/selected-articles</id>
                <rel>o</rel>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-deadwood/introduction</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
            </result>
        </results>
    </topic>
</topics>
